[
  {
    "id": 0,
    "question": "What you shouldnâ€™t put into the container for glass?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "beer bottle",
      "b": "marmolade jar",
      "c": "cosmetic cream jar",
      "d": "broken glass"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "d"
  },
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "How much CO2 is created from burning one litre of gasoline?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "576 grams",
      "b": "8,7 kilograms",
      "c": "2.35 kilograms",
      "d": "17 grams"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "c"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "How much water is needed to produce one cotton T-shirt?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "15 litres",
      "b": "2700 litres",
      "c": "675 litres",
      "d": "87 litres"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "c"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Which country from the list owns the most resources of drinking water?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "Mali",
      "b": "Poland",
      "c": "Lithuania",
      "d": "Switzerland"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "a"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "What is the most polluting waste in the oceans?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "plastic bags",
      "b": "straws",
      "c": "cigarettes",
      "d": "food wrappers"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "c"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "What food requires the least amount of water per 1 kg to be produced?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "wheat",
      "b": "beef",
      "c": "pork",
      "d": "vegetables"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "d"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which of these items can't be recycled?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "used pizza box",
      "b": "wine glasses",
      "c": "kitchen foil",
      "d": "diapers"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "c"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "What is the cleanest mean of transportation?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "bike",
      "b": "car",
      "c": "train",
      "d": "plane"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "a"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Empty milk carton belongs to:",
    "answers": {
      "a": "plastic and metal waste bin",
      "b": "paper bin",
      "c": "glass bin",
      "d": "hazardous waste bin"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "a"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Which fuel produces the most emissions?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "coal",
      "b": "wood pellet",
      "c": "wood",
      "d": "natural gas"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "c"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "What is the main cause, that makes polypropylene and polyethylene very hard to recycle?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "they differ with color",
      "b": "they melt in different temperatures",
      "c": "they can not mix together",
      "d": "they are too light"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "c"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "What is on top of the Waste Hierarchy tool?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "minimisation",
      "b": "recycling",
      "c": "prevention",
      "d": "reuse"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "c"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "How can you reduce the amount of waste?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "only buy what you really have to",
      "b": "do not keep garbage in your home",
      "c": "it is not possible",
      "d": "crush your waste"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "a"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Who is responsible for taking care of the environment?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "everyone",
      "b": "those who are producing waste",
      "c": "government",
      "d": "NGO's"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "a"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Where can you wash yourself to use the least amount of water?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "in the bathtub",
      "b": "in the shower",
      "c": "in the half-filled bathtub",
      "d": "in the pool"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "b"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "What is the color of the List of Threatened Species?",
    "answers": {
      "a": "green",
      "b": "red",
      "c": "blue",
      "d": "black"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "b"
  }
]
